Christopher Robert Hardy

284 Great Road, Apt. A8, Acton, MA 01720 Cell: 609 636 8048

E-mail: christopherhardy@gmail.com

I am an experienced Software Quality Assurance Engineer that specializes in Software Test Automation and Testops.

You might ask what is Testops. It is using Continuous Integration to automatically deploy and test software, write reports for real-time check-in of software and execute Daily Regressions. I trouble shoot with Developers and QA issues that might arise during the Jenkins "Jobs" for each specific set of tests during CI and DR. I configure using the Jenkins UI, a Jenkins plugin, JobDSL or the use of Jenkinsfile configuration.

As a Test Automation Engineer, I use various tools such as SoapUI, JMeter and write custom middle and back-end test automation software to test Desktop and Web applications APIs. I am able to write Test Plans, Test Strategies, and formulate extensive Test Procedures and Test Cases.

If you want a very well rounded Testops, QA Test Automation Engineer and Lead then I am your perfect fit. I feel my early experience as a developer has produced a seasoned QA Automation Test Engineer and knowledgeable leader through the years.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, Groovy, SQL, XML, JSON, Bash Databases: Oracle 11, MySQL, DB2, Cassandra

O/S: Linux, and Windows
Software: Intellij, Eclipse, SoapUI, vi

Tools: Jenkins, Git, GitHub, TestNG, JUnit, CVS, JIRA, RTC

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IBM – Watson Health Imaging

Cambridge, MA

Nov. 2016 – Present

QA Automation Engineer – Testops - Devops

IBM Watson Health

Skills Utilized: Java, Junit, TestNG, Jenkins, Groovy, bash, Linux, Agile, Eclipse, Intellij, SQL, RTC, GitHub, JIRA

Use Devops knowledge to create a process and environments for the Watson Health Imaging team. Teaching various classes around Testops and Agile methodologies. Designing a robust QA Automation framework using TestNG and JUnit to test the UI and Web Service APIs. Worked with the team on various Demo and Prototype products.

IBM – Watson Core Littleton, MA April 2015 – Oct. 2016

Testops - QA Automation Engineer IBM Watson

Contractor - NewGen

Skills Utilized: Jenkins, Java, Groovy, Bash, Linux, Agile, Eclipse, Intellij, SQL, RTC, GitHub

Since February I have been involved testing applications for the IBM Watson project. I focused mainly on QA automation of the REST API's within the application. I used custom java API's to thoroughly test over 20 micro services in a short amount of time. I will be soon working towards automating the front-end with Selenium and Cucumber.

I spent my first 10 months as a Testops engineer. I supported the entire IBM Watson QA Automation Group. I utilized Jenkins as a tool to create an environment for QA team to have an automated Continuous Integration and automated DR (Daily Regression) suites. I handled daily DR Review for all of QA, major and minor issues on a priority basis, and enhanced the current Jenkins configurations for all jobs. Pro-grammatically I have started to implement JobDSL, a framework for Jenkins that allows one to code the configurations for your entire Jenkins framework instead of one job at a time. I also handle the Release Coordination of each three-week sprint for the review of the Daily Regressions.

EDUCATION

| Villanova University | Philadelphia, PA | Jun 2010 – Dec 2010 |
|----------------------------------|------------------|---------------------|
| Contificate Took For the continu | | |

Certificate Test Engineering

Rowan University Glassboro, NJ Sept 1997 – May 2001

Bachelor of Computer Science

Ocean County College Toms River, NJ Sept 1993 – May 1997

A.S in General Engineering

Activities/Other work experience:

- Free Masonry Junior Steward and Inside Sentinel, Service Project Lead and District and Blue Lodge Webmaster
- Alpha Chi Rho Fraternity President, Vice-President and Risk Management.
- Six Flags Great Adventure Supervisor, Manager and Point of sale technician.
- Air Force ROTC Vice-President, Operations Officer, Color Guard Officer.

Additional PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Scholastic Watertown, MA Sept 2014– March 2015

Lead QA Engineer Scholastic

Contractor — Addison Group

Skills Utilized: JMeter, Java, Agile, Xml, Eclipse, SQL, Git, Linux, JIRA, Confluence, HP Quality Center

Lead QA Engineer of a few teams for Scent 2.0 Platform. Designed and implemented a JMeter test framework to test various web services for the new Scent 2.0 Core Platform. Learned TDD and ATDD methodologies using JUnit, Cucumber and JMeter. Created test cases for defects in the SAM product line and tested them. Executed regression testing for SAM product line and regression tested various products.

HealthEdge Burlington, MA Dec 2012 – May 2014

QA Automation Engineer <u>HealthEdge</u>

Skills Utilized: Java, JUnit, Agile, Xml, Eclipse, SQL, Perforce, Linux, JIRA, SoapUI, Groovy

Designed the automation test framework for the Care Admin interface using Java. Manually tested and created test plans for the UI mapping, regression tests and business scenario tests that laid out the entire test coverage for the interface between two applications. Helped with the process using agile methodologies as a scrum master and active participant in every standup, story time, retrospective and sprint planning per two-week sprint. Spoke with the VP of my group and we discussed what we could do in a step by step manner to roll out a better scrum based process. In doing so we stream lined all aspects one would call the scrum process.

EMC - RSA Bedford, MA May 2012 - Dec 2012

QA Automation Engineer RSA-EMC

Contractor – Vesume Group

Skills Utilized: Java, Groovy, SoapUI, Agile, Xml, Eclipse, SQL, Jenkins, Windows, JIRA

Designed the automation test framework using the SoapUI tool. Solved the problem of how to use the SoapUI too to meet the test automation requirements. Manually tested and frequently found bugs, about 33% better rate within the web browser for the application UI. I solved the problem where test automation was lacking to shorten the manual testing, in turn all regression testing that was manual was on its way to be automated with a test coverage of at least 50%-60%. The team and I first off discussed what tools we could use before writing custom Java test automation code. Once we decided on the tool, SoapUI, we designed a framework around SoapUI and then once we found out the best use of the tool, we started to write the custom data creation code and a more robust custom test automation framework.

Contractor – Minuteman Group

Skills Utilized: Java, Groovy, Agile, XML, Eclipse, Linux, TestNG, SQL, MVN, SVN, Hudson, Windows

Designed the test automation framework and over 200 test cases for the project starting with zero test cases. Worked with co-worker to create smoke test and regression test tools to report results daily which gave the lead, developers and QA a better idea very early on when code breaks the regression test automation test cases. Pioneered the design of a XML checker to test the most current XML schemas. The XML checker allowed instant checks for all schemas at an instant 2-3 times during the two week sprint which made developers and QA to be in-sync in regard to the test data and the most current schemas. This eventually got folded into the regression testing which was done each night during build process, which previously caused daily delays in test-deployment were no longer an issue with the use of the XML checker.

proServicesCorp Feb 2008 - June 2010 Trenton, NJ proServicesCorp

QA Engineer

Process Developer/Tester and Defect Analysis

Skills Utilized: Java, Eclipse, Linux, Windows

DSCI – Information Assurance Ft. Monmouth, NJ Jun 2007 - Feb 2008

Software Engineer III DSCI

RDECOM - S&TCD Contractor

Skills Utilized: Linux, Windows

BAE Systems Mar 2006 - June 2007 Wayne, NJ

Principal Engineer BAE Systems

Skills Utilized: C++, CORBA, XML, Green Hills INTEGRITY 5.0.6

Lockheed Martin Mar 2005 – Feb 2006 Moorestown, NJ

Member of the Engineering Staff **Lockheed Martin**

Skills Utilized: Visual C++, Windows

Computer Science Corporation Mt. Laurel, NJ Jun 2001 – Mar 2005

Associate Member of the Technical Staff **CSC**

Skills Utilized: C++, Ada, UNIX